<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.1">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2023-09-21T16:25:46+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/</id>

  
    <title type="html">NauticApp</title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Real-Time GPS Tracking and Speed, Responsive Magnetic Heading (CoG), Position, Chartplotter (with automatically updated chart data), Weather Full Forecast, Compass and Logbook..</subtitle>
  

  

  
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Smart Boating and NautiGuard: A New Era of Boating Innovation</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Smart Boating and NautiGuard: A New Era of Boating Innovation" />
      <published>2023-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2023-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/feature-3</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Welcome to NauticApp, where innovation meets the high seas! In this post, we&apos;re excited to introduce you to two of our game-changing features: Smart Boating and NautiGuard.&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart Boating: Your Ultimate Boating Companion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smart Boating is the heart of NauticApp, revolutionizing the way you experience life on the water. It’s your ultimate boating companion, seamlessly integrating cutting-edge technology into your maritime adventures. Here’s what Smart Boating brings to your fingertips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real-Time GPS Tracking:&lt;/strong&gt; Stay on course with precision and confidence using our real-time GPS tracking feature. Know your exact location, speed, and heading at all times.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Responsive Magnetic Heading (CoG):&lt;/strong&gt; Navigate with ease using our responsive magnetic heading indicator, ensuring you’re always on the right path.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Position and Chartplotter:&lt;/strong&gt; Explore the open waters with our intuitive position and chartplotter, powered by the mapbox_gl Flutter plugin.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weather Full Forecast:&lt;/strong&gt; Plan your journey with confidence, thanks to our weather full forecast powered by OpenWeather. Stay ahead of changing conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compass and Logbook:&lt;/strong&gt; Keep a digital log of your voyages and rely on our precise compass for accurate direction.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marine IoT Integration:&lt;/strong&gt; Connect your microcontrollers and sensors to NauticApp for seamless data integration. Monitor, control, and optimize your boat’s systems like never before.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marine Engineering Hub:&lt;/strong&gt; Troubleshoot engine issues, maintain schedules, manage spare parts, and monitor engine performance all in one dedicated hub.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Safety Checklist:&lt;/strong&gt; Ensure your vessel’s safety with a comprehensive checklist, providing peace of mind for every journey.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NautiGuard: Unleashing IoT Potential&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NautiGuard is where the future of boating innovation unfolds. It’s a series of small IoT projects, each designed to enhance your boating experience and integrate seamlessly with NauticApp. Here’s a glimpse of what NautiGuard has in store:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BilgeMonitor:&lt;/strong&gt; Already discussed in detail in our previous post, BilgeMonitor keeps your boat dry by monitoring water levels and automatically activating the bilge pump when needed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anemometer (Wind Sensor):&lt;/strong&gt; Stay ahead of changing wind conditions with real-time wind speed and direction data.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Depth Sounder:&lt;/strong&gt; Get insights into water depth, critical for safe navigation in varying terrains.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Temperature and Humidity Sensors:&lt;/strong&gt; Keep tabs on onboard conditions for comfort and safety.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Engine Sensors:&lt;/strong&gt; Monitor your engine’s vital statistics in real-time, ensuring optimal performance and early issue detection.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Safety Sensors:&lt;/strong&gt; Enhance onboard safety with sensors designed to detect fire, gas leaks, and other potential hazards.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for more in-depth discussions on each NautiGuard project, and get ready to elevate your boating experience with NauticApp’s Smart Boating and NautiGuard features. The future of boating has arrived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
        <summary type="html">Welcome to NauticApp, where innovation meets the high seas! In this post, we&apos;re excited to introduce you to two of our game-changing features: Smart Boating and NautiGuard.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">NautiGuard BilgeMonitor: Your Boat’s Guardian</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NautiGuard BilgeMonitor: Your Boat&apos;s Guardian" />
      <published>2023-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2023-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/feature-2</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;This ingenious device is your boat&apos;s guardian against unwanted water intrusions. Let&apos;s explore what the BilgeMonitor has to offer:&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bilgemonitor-keeping-your-boat-dry&quot;&gt;BilgeMonitor: Keeping Your Boat Dry&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real-Time Water Level Tracking&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say goodbye to worries about water accumulating in your boat’s bilge. The BilgeMonitor provides real-time water level tracking, keeping you informed about any rising water levels, no matter where you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automatic Bilge Pump Control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the BilgeMonitor detects an elevated water level, it takes action swiftly. It automatically activates the bilge pump, sparing you the hassle of manual intervention and ensuring your vessel stays dry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remote Access via NauticApp&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re always connected to your boat, thanks to NautiGuard’s seamless integration with NauticApp. Monitor your bilge remotely, receive alerts, and take control from anywhere in the world using your smartphone or tablet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peace of Mind, Always&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the BilgeMonitor on board, you can enjoy your boating adventures with peace of mind. Whether you’re at the helm or miles away, your boat’s safety is in good hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for more NautiGuard projects, each designed to enhance your boating experience. The BilgeMonitor is just the beginning of a new era of boating safety and convenience. Happy sailing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
        <summary type="html">This ingenious device is your boat&apos;s guardian against unwanted water intrusions. Let&apos;s explore what the BilgeMonitor has to offer:</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">borrar</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="borrar" />
      <published>2023-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2023-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/feature-1</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Welcome to NauticApp, where innovation meets the high seas! In this post, we&apos;re excited to introduce you to two of our game-changing features: Smart Boating and NautiGuard.&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart Boating: Your Ultimate Boating Companion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smart Boating is the heart of NauticApp, revolutionizing the way you experience life on the water. It’s your ultimate boating companion, seamlessly integrating cutting-edge technology into your maritime adventures. Here’s what Smart Boating brings to your fingertips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real-Time GPS Tracking:&lt;/strong&gt; Stay on course with precision and confidence using our real-time GPS tracking feature. Know your exact location, speed, and heading at all times.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Responsive Magnetic Heading (CoG):&lt;/strong&gt; Navigate with ease using our responsive magnetic heading indicator, ensuring you’re always on the right path.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Position and Chartplotter:&lt;/strong&gt; Explore the open waters with our intuitive position and chartplotter, powered by the mapbox_gl Flutter plugin.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weather Full Forecast:&lt;/strong&gt; Plan your journey with confidence, thanks to our weather full forecast powered by OpenWeather. Stay ahead of changing conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compass and Logbook:&lt;/strong&gt; Keep a digital log of your voyages and rely on our precise compass for accurate direction.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marine IoT Integration:&lt;/strong&gt; Connect your microcontrollers and sensors to NauticApp for seamless data integration. Monitor, control, and optimize your boat’s systems like never before.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marine Engineering Hub:&lt;/strong&gt; Troubleshoot engine issues, maintain schedules, manage spare parts, and monitor engine performance all in one dedicated hub.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Safety Checklist:&lt;/strong&gt; Ensure your vessel’s safety with a comprehensive checklist, providing peace of mind for every journey.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Battery monitors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These provide information on the state of your boat’s batteries, including voltage, current, and remaining capacity. By integrating battery monitors with Signal K, this data can be easily transmitted and displayed in real-time on NauticApp. When selecting a battery monitor, it’s important to consider the accuracy, compatibility with Signal K, and the ability to connect to your boat’s battery system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tank Level Sensors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Water and fuel tank sensors provide information on the level and remaining capacity of your boat’s water and fuel tanks. By integrating these sensors with Signal K, this data can be easily transmitted and displayed in real-time on NauticApp. When selecting water and fuel tank sensors, it’s important to consider the compatibility with Signal K, the type of tank (e.g. plastic, metal), and the measurement range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Temperature and Humidity Sensors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explain how temperature and humidity sensors can be useful for monitoring the interior conditions of a boat. Provide examples of popular temperature and humidity sensors that can be integrated with NauticApp through Signal K.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Depth Sensors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This kind of sensors provide information on water depth, helping sailors navigate safely and avoid running aground. When selecting a depth sensor, it’s important to consider the measurement range, accuracy, and compatibility with Signal K.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
        <summary type="html">Welcome to NauticApp, where innovation meets the high seas! In this post, we&apos;re excited to introduce you to two of our game-changing features: Smart Boating and NautiGuard.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
